<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-08T17:09:42+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Let’s Talk Payments</title><subtitle>Just Another Jekyll Theme</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Helping Insurers Adjust to the New Reality of the Sharing Economy – Interview With Brad Weisberg, CEO &amp;amp; Founder of Snapsheet</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/06/interview-with-brad-weisberg-ceo-founder-snapsheet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Helping Insurers Adjust to the New Reality of the Sharing Economy – Interview With Brad Weisberg, CEO &amp; Founder of Snapsheet" /><published>2017-12-06T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-12-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/06/interview-with-brad-weisberg-ceo-founder-snapsheet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/06/interview-with-brad-weisberg-ceo-founder-snapsheet.html">&lt;p&gt;The LTP Team had a pleasure to interview Brad Weisberg, CEO &amp;amp; Founder of Snapsheet, provider of virtual claims technology used by auto insurance carriers to optimize workflows, speed up claims processes and provide superior service to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy our interview with Brad as much as we did! &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helping Insurers Adjust to the New Reality of the Sharing Economy – Interview With Brad Weisberg, CEO &amp;amp; Founder of Snapsheet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brad Weisberg, CEO &amp;amp; Founder of Snapsheet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LTP: Brad, a pleasure to speak with you. Please tell us a little bit about yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brad Weisberg: I am the CEO and co-founder of Snapsheet, a leading provider of virtual claims technology. Before founding Snapsheet, I was drawn to the innovation and nimbleness of the startup world and served as the VP of global sales at Where I’ve Been, which was acquired by TripAdvisor in 2011. I continue to champion the startup community and am passionate about bringing creative people together to solve today’s complex problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LTP: Give us a paragraph pitch of your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BW: Snapsheet is the pioneering provider of virtual claims technology used by auto insurance carriers to optimize workflows, speed up claims processes and provide superior service to their customers. Our cloud-based software enables carriers to virtually process a claim with photos taken by the user via their smartphone. Through a multitude of technologies housed on our platform, we’re able to help insurance providers process claims quicker, allowing customers to be paid faster and back in safe, repaired vehicles sooner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LTP: What problem are you solving today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BW: We’re solving a variety of problems, as Snapsheet’s workflow improvements encompass all stages of the claims process. We help carriers and their claimants step-by-step through the entire claims journey, from first notice of loss and estimation, all the way to repair and payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even now, the insurance industry relies heavily on legacy technology and manual processes. Nearly all claims payments are still paid by check, which can be a costly and burdensome experience. To solve this problem, Snapsheet came together with KeyBank to create Snapsheet Transactions, a solution that enables carriers to pay claimants virtually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LTP: Who are you selling to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BW: Our customers are insurance carriers. Our role is to work closely with carriers, not disrupt the industry. Thanks to partnerships with carriers, we’re on track to process about 450,000 claims this year. With the launch of Snapsheet Transactions, we are able to expand our customer base beyond auto insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LTP: Why did you start the company?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BW: After graduating from Indiana University, I moved to L.A. to work as a production assistant for HBO. On my way to work one day, I got into a fender bender. I took my car to three different body shops, and received three completely different estimates. Throughout this painful and long experience, I thought to myself, “There’s got to be an easier way.” I pooled all of my savings together and founded BodyShopBids, which later evolved into Snapsheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move from BodyShopBids to Snapsheet happened in 2013. We determined that targeting consumers directly was not a sustainable business model. At the recommendation of a customer, we pivoted to working with insurance carriers. He introduced us to carriers who were very interested in the product, and we rebranded to Snapsheet. Although changing the direction of the company was challenging, there is no doubt that this was the right move for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LTP: What’s the most important change coming to your segment in the next 3-5 years?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BW: There’s a straight line between the expansion of the sharing economy and the rise of InsurTech. As the sharing economy is embraced by late adopters, there will be a massive shift in consumer expectations, and InsurTech such as ours will be there to help insurance carriers adjust to these shifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LTP: What’s your next milestone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BW: Recently, we came together with KeyBank, one of the largest bank-based financial services companies in the United States, for the launch of Snapsheet Transactions. Together with KeyBank’s treasury knowledge and our insurance workflows expertise, we provide the technology needed to simplify claims and offer the optimal customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a significant need for digital payments. Looking at natural disasters like Hurricane Harvey, the importance of digital payments is more apparent than ever. After a hurricane, or any disaster for that matter, people can’t wait to receive a check in the mail. Snapsheet Transactions solves that problem for carriers and claimants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LTP: What’s one thing you wish customers knew before a sales meeting?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BW: I wish customers knew how essential a good understanding of insurance workflows is, which other InsurTech companies don’t always have. Because we have a strong foundation with carriers, implementing Snapsheet is easy and the onboarding process for new clients is seamless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LTP: What keeps you awake at night?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BW: The fact that there is a better way and many people are going through countless hoops and not getting the answers they need. There’s no reason for that with the technology Snapsheet has made available to carriers. We have helped solve a big problem and it is important that more people have access to our solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LTP: Anything else you want to say to our audience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BW: Our aim is to make the entire claims process simple for everyone, so we’re constantly looking for ways to meet customer expectations that are actionable for carriers. Creating Snapsheet Transactions is just one step toward creating a seamless process from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LTP Team: Thank you, Brad!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ASIA" /><category term="EUROPE" /><category term="INSIGHTS" /><category term="US" /><summary type="html">The LTP Team had a pleasure to interview Brad Weisberg, CEO &amp;amp; Founder of Snapsheet, provider of virtual claims technology used by auto insurance carriers to optimize workflows, speed up claims processes and provide superior service to their customers. We hope you enjoy our interview with Brad as much as we did!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Review The Global Race for Real-Time Payments</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/05/daily-review-global-race-for-real-time-payments.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Review The Global Race for Real-Time Payments" /><published>2017-12-05T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-12-05T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/05/daily-review-global-race-for-real-time-payments</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/05/daily-review-global-race-for-real-time-payments.html">&lt;p&gt;“The brave new world of global finance is getting braver. Real-time and near-real-time payments systems have changed the fabric of online commerce.” – Patricia Pozuelo, Enterprise Technology Specialist, Intel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Global Race for Real-Time Payments &lt;!--more--&gt;
30+ countries have real-time payment processes of some kind (for example, Faster Payments in the UK, Singapore’s FAST); several have been in use for decades.
The reasons the US lags in development of its own RTP system: 1. The sheer number of financial institutions in the country compared to the rest of the world – the US has roughly 5,300 commercial banks and more than 6,000 credit unions; 2. Complicated regulations process; 3. The US’ complex regulatory process – 50 regulators + more than 20 federal agencies that all need to provide approval in order to implement RTP restructuring. The UK has one single agency.
The majority of Europe is already onboard with these streamlining banking upgrades as well, with countries like Spain, Denmark, Sweden, Poland, and the Netherlands putting RTP services into practice nationally.
The Swiss National Bank has been ahead of the curve since 1987 when it introduced its 24-hour payment-processing SIC system and revolutionized the world of pre-internet banking.
China’s mobile and digital payment market was the largest in the world, at $1.83 trillion in 2016. Most of that activity comes from two companies: Alipay and Tenpay.&lt;br /&gt;
Japan has had their Zengin System running near-RTP for years, which is about to get an upgrade. SBI Ripple Asia recently announced the creation of a consortium of 42 member banks that will use Ripple’s new round-the-clock blockchain technology for payments and settlement.
The rest of the industrialized world has already implemented or started implementing fast-payment systems, including Nigeria, South Africa, Brazil, Chile, Mexico, India, and Australia.
US p2p payments users are expected to grow to 126 million by 2020, with non-banks leading much of the charge. WEF estimates that 80% of banks are currently developing blockchain projects. 19 of the biggest financial firms in the US all signed on for a new p2p payments network Zelle.
FIS and The Clearing House also launched a nationwide RTP system during the first quarter of 2017, which could garner up to $1.1 billion in revenues. Both banks are also members of the Federal Reserve’s Faster Payments Task Force Steering Committee, which will soon start evaluating new approaches for implementing RTP across the country.
Read more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morgan Stanley Undercuts Rivals With Robo
Morgan Stanley has launched its online platform, Access Investing, with an annual fee below those of its wirehouse rivals. The program fee: 0.35% of assets under management per year. The robo portfolios include mutual funds and ETFs with both active and passive strategies. They also feature automated rebalancing and tax-loss harvesting at no additional charge.
Merrill Edge Guided Investing robo-service charges 0.45%, and Wells Fargo’s Intuitive Investor offering has a 0.50% fee. Discount brokerages Schwab, Fidelity and Vanguard all charge less than Morgan Stanley for advisor-focused robo services: 0.28% for Schwab Intelligent Advisor, 0.30% for Vanguard Personal Advisor Services and 0.15% for Fidelity AMP. These fees don’t include expenses on the underlying funds.
While Morgan Stanley’s has a $5,000 account minimum, competing Wells Fargo service can be accessed with $10,000 or more of client assets.
“Morgan Stanley Access Investing is an opportunity for financial advisors to grow their book of business by making connections with prospects earlier and eventually establishing full-service relationships when clients are ready.” – Morgan Stanley Chief Digital Officer Naureen Hassan.
Read more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Target Launches Wallet in the Target App: A Faster, Easier Way to Pay and Save
Target introduced Wallet in the Target app – a new way for guests to pay and save at Target stores. With Wallet, guests can pay using their Target REDcard and save with Cartwheel — all in a single scan of their phones at checkout.
Target claims the in-store checkout time with the new Wallet is up to four times faster than other payment types.
The Wallet combines digital savings—Cartwheel offers and Weekly Ad coupons—with the 5% REDcard discount.
Coming soon, guests also will be able to store and redeem Target GiftCards with Wallet.
Read more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like our daily reviews? Follow us on Twitter, LinkedIn, and Medium for the latest updates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Featured image credit: OpenMarkets.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ASIA" /><category term="INSIGHTS" /><summary type="html">“The brave new world of global finance is getting braver. Real-time and near-real-time payments systems have changed the fabric of online commerce.” – Patricia Pozuelo, Enterprise Technology Specialist, Intel The Global Race for Real-Time Payments</summary></entry></feed>